Most people lose their job offers for us stupid reason. Not skills, not interviews, but references.
Ik kahane sonatao. You've been at a job for two years. Good relationship with your manager. They know your work. They rate you.
You eventually decide to move on. You resign professionally. Everything is fine. 18 months later. You're applying for a serious role. You've nailed the interviews. You're basically the preferred candidate. They ask you for two references.
You think of your old manager. You searched for the email. But they left the company eight months ago.
You don't have their personal email. Their LinkedIn hasn't been updated. The old work number goes nowhere.
You are now delying the reference check on a job offer that's sitting open waiting for you to close it. And some companies will take away the offer if the reference check takes too long.
All of that because you didn't do one simple thing before you left that job.
Before you leave any job in Australia, get your references sorted while you're still there. Ask your manager directly. Would you be comfortable being a reference for me in the future?
Get their personal email. Get their personal phone number. Connect on LinkedIn immediately. Do it in your final week. Not after you're left. Not six months later.
Because once you're gone, people move on. Companies restructure. Emails get deactivated.
And the best references you ever had becomes completely unreachable at the exact moment you need them most.
Your reference list is an asset in Australia protected like one.